Today, we have our
co-instructor, Div,
talking about human inspired
approaches to agents
and how the path to AGI
requires a rethinking of how
we design, evaluate,
and deploy intelligence.
Div Garg is the founder and
CEO of AGI Incorporated,
a new applied AI lab
redefining AI human interaction
with the mission to bring
AGI into everyday life.
Div previously founded
MultiOn, the first AI agent
startup, developing agents that
can interact with computers
and assist with everyday tasks,
funded by top Silicon Valley
VCs.
Div has spent his career at
the intersection of AI research
and startups and was previously
a CS PhD student here
at Stanford, focused on RL.
His work spans across
various high impact areas,
ranging from self-driving cars,
robotics, computer control,
and Minecraft AI agents.
With that, I'll hand it to him.
take.
It away.
Yes, excited to be here.
Great.
So yeah, excited to be here.
And the topic for
this lecture is
we want to talk about
a lot of new things
that are happening in
the AI world right now.
So there's been a lot of
developments with agents
And all the new models
that are coming out.
And it seems like you have
some of superintelligence when
it comes to chat and
reasoning already there,
compared to average humans.
And it's going to
be very interesting,
over the next few years,
as we figure out what
does intelligence look like?
What is something like AGI?
And what's the form factor?
How can this be
something that's useful?
And how will this be
applied in society?
Cool.
So let's take the first
thing we want to touch on.
What does AGI look like?
AGI is such an abstract
concept right now.
No one has visualized it
or given it a meaning.
Is this some sort
of supercomputer?
Is it just like ChatGPT
but just 10x better?
Is it something that's more
of a personal companion?
It's something that's
embedded in your life.
And that's not clear yet.
And those are the
questions, I think,
we really need to
go and figure out.
This is one diagram
on how AI agents work.
So this is an architecture from
a OpenAI researcher Lillian
Wang.
She recently left and
joined a new company.
So this is showing how
you can think about agents
and how they can be broken
down into different subparts.
And there's a lot
of different things
that you require to
make this agents work.
So the first layer is memory.
You need to have some
short-term memory.
You want to have some
of long term memory.
And this is, like, you have
some short representation that's
maybe a chat window if
you're using ChatGPT.
And you might also have a
personal history of the user
where, OK, this is maybe
what the user likes.
This is what they don't like.
The second thing that
you need is tools.
You want this kind of agents
to be able to use tools
like how humans use tools.
So you want them to be
able to use calculators.
You want them to be able to use
calendars, web search, coding,
and so on.
The third part over here is you
want to have advanced planning.
And that means you
want to-- the agents
to be able to use reflection,
where if something goes wrong,
they can have
failover mechanisms,
error correct, and recover.
You want self-criticism.
And you want a
decomposition, where
you have chains of thoughts.
So the agent can do their
own reasoning loops.
They can also break down a
complex task into subgoals.
And the final
fourth ingredient is
actions, where you
want these agents
to be able to act on your
behalf and go do things.
And this is high
level encapsulates
how agents look
like, fundamentally.
And this is maybe what will--
as these systems become
more powerful over time,
will eventually lead to
something that's like AGI.
This is one thing that
we're also building.
So I recently started this new
AI lab called AGI Incorporated.
And we're looking a lot into,
like, what does AGI look
like for everyday purposes?
And how can this be
applied to daily life?
This is one of the demos
of some technologies
we built in the past.
This shows how an AI agent can
be applied in the real world.
So this is a bit old.
And it shows how
an AI agent can be
applied to pass a real
driving test in California.
And so this is an actual DMV
test that the agent took.
Let me share the screen
and talk about the setup.
So in this screen,
what's happening is
there's someone attempting
the DMV online test.
There's a human who has their
hands over the keyboard.
They're not actually
touching the screen.
And it's an agent that's going
and taking all the exams.
And there's 40
questions in this test.
And the agent is really good.
So it can go and
pass the whole thing.
And we did this live.
So the DMV was actually screen
recording what we're doing.
They were also watching
the person on camera.
But even then, the
agent was successfully
able to evade the whole
setup and pass the exam.
So this was really fun.
We did this as a
[INAUDIBLE] attempt,
so we informed the DMV
afterwards that we did this.
Funnily enough, they actually
sent us a driving license,
afterwards.
So that was really
fun, actually.
So at the end, the agent is
able to pass and get a pass,
get a full score
on this test here.
And so yeah, so this is
a very fun experiment
showing how agents can be
applied in the real world.
And there's so many
things that are possible.
In this vein, how can we
make agents more useful,
apply them in real life.
We have been working on a
lot of different efforts,
along with a lot of
the AI community.
One of those things
is agent evaluations.
How can we evaluate this kind
of agents in the real world
and make sure we have
standards and benchmarks that
allows us to know, how well
are these agents working
on different websites
or different use cases?
How can we trust them?
How can know where to deploy
them and how to use them?
Another thing we are doing have
been doing is agent training.
Can we train agents
to be able to do
advanced planning,
self-correction,
and improve themselves?
And this uses a combination
of reinforcement learning
and a bunch of other
advanced techniques.
And finally, we have
also been looking a lot
into agent communication.
How can you have an agent
communicate with other agents?
And there's been a lot of new
breakthroughs in this area,
recently.
So if you've looked at
model context protocol MCP,
that's a very new thing
that has been coming out.
Similarly, there's a
lot of work around A2A,
that's Google's Agent2Agent
communication protocol that
recently came out.
We also have been working on
some open source projects called
Agent protocol, where
we have been allowing
other different kind of agents
to communicate to each other.
So you can have a
coding agent that
can talk to a web agent that
can talk to an API based agent
and so on.
And that allows you to do
much, much more complex things
than what's possible
with just a single agent.
Cool.
So before we dive more deeper
into how a lot of these things
works, I want to bring out,
like, why do we need agents?
Why are they useful?
Why do we actually want
to go and build them?
And there's a lot of things
we need to think about here.
And I will touch on a
lot of different topics
in the introduction, going
from the architectures,
building more human-like agents,
using computer interactions,
maybe memory communication, and
what are the future directions.
So when you think
about building agents,
there's a lot of things,
questions you have to answer.
The first one is,
why is this useful?
How can you actually build them?
What are the different
building blocks?
And finally, what
can you do with them?
And to first answer
the why question,
we have this key
thesis that agents
will be more efficient
in interfacing
with computers in the digital
world compared to humans.
And that's the reason that we
want to go and apply agents
to be able to do things for us.
So you can imagine you have
an army of virtual assistants
that are fully digital,
that can go and do
whatever you want
on your behalf.
And you can just talk to
them using a human interface.
And that's the vision we
have been moving towards.
I also have a blog post about
this called Software 3.0
that you can check
out, which touches
upon some of those ideas.
Cool.
So we want to go
and build agents
because, usually, large language
models are not good enough.
And we want action
capabilities that
allows us to unlock more
productivity and go do things.
And this also allows us to
build more complex systems.
There's a lot of techniques
involved in actually building
this, such as chaining
different models together,
reflection, and a bunch
of other mechanisms.
And as I showed before in the
architecture, on slide two,
there's a lot of different
components-- memory,
actions, personalization, access
to the internet, and so on.
And finally, the
question becomes,
what are the
different applications
we can apply them to?
There's also a
question of, why do
we want to build
human-like agents?
Why can't we just
have API agents?
Or why can't we have a bunch
of other kind of agents
you can imagine, which are not
mimicking human interactions?
And one reason we want to push
towards more human-like agents
is these agents can operate
interfaces like how we do.
And usually, the
internet, and the web,
and computers are
designed for humans.
So they're designed for
keyboard and mouse interactions,
so that we can go and
navigate interfaces.
We can use our keyboards.
And if agents are able to
use interfaces like we do,
that allows them to
directly communicate and do
a lot of things without
changing how current software
programs work.
And that becomes
very, very effective
because that allows you to
work on 100% of the internet
without any bottlenecks.
If you think about
APIs, there's only 5%
of APIs on the internet are
public that are accessible.
And it's very hard
to build agents that
are fully reliable over APIs.
And so there's a
lot of contention
between human-like
agents versus API agents.
And that's an ongoing battle
that's happening right now.
Second thing is you can imagine
a lot of human-like agents
as becoming a digital
extension of you.
So they can learn about you.
They can have a
context about you.
They can do tasks like
how you will do it.
They also have less
restrictive boundaries.
This kind of human-like
agents can handle logins,
they can handle payments.
And they're able to interact
with any of the services
without restrictions
in terms of API access.
So you don't need to
pay for using an API
or you don't need to go
to a service provider
and ask them for, can you
give me access to this API?
You can just go and use an
interface like you normally do.
And the final thing is there's
a very simple action space.
This agents only need to
learn how to click and type.
And if they're able to
do that very effectively,
they can generalize
to any interface.
And they can also
improve over time.
So the more you teach them, the
more data you can give them.
They can learn from user
recordings, feedback,
and become better
and better over time.
And so when it comes to this
API versus more direct computer
control agents, these are how we
think about the pros and cons.
API agents are usually
easier to build.
They are more controllable.
They are more safer.
But APIs are more
have high viability.
So you have to build
different agents for each API.
And then APIs can keep changing.
You never have a full guarantee
that this agent will always
work 100%.
When it comes to this
more direct interaction
computer controlled agents,
it's easier to take actions,
in this case.
It's also more
freeform interactions
because you're not restricted
by the API boundaries.
But it's also hard
to provide guarantees
because you don't know
what the agent will do.
So if anyone here has played
with agents like Operator,
it's a work in progress.
It's not really there.
There's a lot of issues
that it turns into.
And that's the boundaries
where agents are right now.
There's also different
levels of autonomy
when you think about agents.
This is usually goes
from level 1 to level 5.
So level 1 to level 2 is
when a human is in control
and the agent is
acting like a co-pilot.
So it's helping the human.
And so this is something
like if you've used
like a code editor like Cursor.
That's a L2 agent, where you
have partial automation, where
the human is in control, the
human is writing the code,
but the agent is helping them.
When it comes to
something like L3,
this is where there's still
a human fallback mechanism,
but the agent is in control.
So this is if you use Cursor
Composer, or Windsurf, or any
of the newer code editors
that are more agentic.
The agent is writing
most of the code,
but a human is monitoring,
giving it feedback.
OK, this went wrong.
Can you correct that for me?
Can you fix this issue?
And that is more of a L3 system.
And then you have
more advanced systems
which are like L4 and L5.
And L4 systems, you don't
have a human in the loop.
So it's the agent that's
going and doing everything.
You might still have some of
automated fallback layers.
So if you look at Waymo
in SF, that's an L4 system
because the self-driving
car is driving itself,
but there's human
operators that are
remotely monitoring it, making
sure nothing goes wrong.
And then you have L5 system.
In that case, there's
no humans in the loop.
There's no monitoring.
And the AI agent is able to
operate itself autonomously,
fully, fully, independently.
So when we are building this
agents, one hard thing is trust.
How do we trust these
agents are actually
going to go do what
we want them to do?
How can we go and deploy
them in the real world?
To solve these
issues, one effort
that we have been building
is a miniature version
of the internet, where
we have cloned the top 20
websites on the internet.
And we are benchmarking,
how do agents go and perform
on all these interfaces?
And this is actually live.
So you can go check
it out, realevals.xyz.
And what we have
done is we have built
digital clones of
websites like Airbnb,
and Amazon, and Door
Dash, and LinkedIn.
And the agents can go and
navigate these interfaces
on predefined tasks.
And you can get a final score.
This is showing the
evolution results for GPT 4o.
We find that GPT 4o, actually,
is not very good on when it
comes to being agentic.
And it only reaches 14%
successful accuracy,
in this case.
We tried this on 11
different environments
that we are showing
on the right.
And we have our
different environments.
We have DashDish, which is our
Door Dash clone, and Omnizon,
and so on.
So you can actually
go and check this out.
We also compare a lot of open
source frameworks out there.
Some of them are like
the OpenAI computer use
model that's powering Operator.
We actually find
it's not very good
when it comes to these tasks.
So it's only able to
reach maximum 20% accuracy
on some of the environments,
like our email environment
or our calendar environments.
But on a lot of the
other environments,
it's not able to actually
go and do really well.
We also tried a bunch of
other frameworks out there--
Stagehand, if you're
familiar-- if you've seen that,
it's an open source
framework for automating
web agents, browser-use, and one
of our own custom agents, which
we're calling Agent-0.
And we find that
agents are still
early when it comes to,
actually, automating
a lot of these interfaces.
And we are able to reach, maybe
I would say, up to 50% success
rate, but a lot of these
agents are actually
failing when you are applying
them in all of these real world
websites.
Similarly, we benchmark
all the different models
that are available, including
all the closed source APIs
and all the open source models.
And we find, again,
on ethnic tasks,
most models are
doing decently well,
but no one is really,
really good right now.
The maximum success we have
seen is with Claude 3.7,
where it can reach
around 40% accuracy.
Gemini 2.5 and O3 follow
very closely with it.
The other models
tend to taper off.
And so the interesting
learning has been,
for us, is that a
lot of these models
are not fully ready to be
deployed in the real world
because if you have, say, an
agent that's powered by Claude
and then you're applying
that, you can only
expect a 41% success rate
that this will actually
go do what you want it to do.
And that's not good enough.
And this brings a
question of, what
is it that is required to
make these agents even better?
How can they improve?
And how can they be applied for
your actual practical use cases?
And so this brings
us to our next topic
for the lecture, which is, how
can we train AI agent models?
So how can we have models that
are more custom fine tuned
and are better on
the generic tasks?
This is one of our past works
called Agent Q, which is
a self-improving agent system.
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[END PLAYBACK]
So this is Agent Q. That's a
system that can self-improve.
It can learn by
corrections and planning.
And how the system works is
it's able to go and self-correct
itself.
So whenever it
makes a mistake, it
can save that mistake
in its past memory.
And it's able to use that to
do a lot of trial and error
learning, similar to humans.
So suppose the first time
you learn how to ride a bike,
you make a lot of mistakes.
You fall over a lot of times.
But over time, you're able
to improve your policy
and go and do that really well.
We apply a similar mechanisms
to make these agents actually
work really, really
well in the real world.
And so what's happening
in the system is
the agent can explore
the space of interfaces
and see, what are the things
that it did that went wrong?
What are the things
that went right?
And it's able to
use reinforcement
learning to self-improve and
become better and better.
So Agent Q combines a S
of different techniques.
The first method is
Monte Carlo Tree Search.
This is borrowed from
other RL techniques
like AlphaGo, that
allow you to plan over
a search space of tasks and
unlock advanced reasoning.
A second thing that we do
is self critic mechanisms.
So the agent can self
verify and get feedback
whenever it makes a mistake.
And it's able to learn
from that feedback.
And finally, we use RLAIF
techniques like DPO,
direct preference
optimization to be
able to improve
the agent using RL.
And by combining all these
three techniques together,
we are able to build some
very powerful systems.
Agent Q is also available on
arXiv as a research paper,
so you go and check it out.
For the sake of time, I will
skip some of the lectures here.
But how Agent Q
normally works is
we have this Monte Carlo Tree
Search, where the agent is
exploring the different states.
It's estimating rewards.
If we were to visit
this state, what's
the expected value of the
future predicted reward?
And based on that, it's able to
improve its prediction model.
Should we go take this path or
a different path in the tree?
And then over time, the
agent can become very good
at exploring the right
states and figuring out,
what are the right paths
in the state space?
And what are the wrong ones?
We also do
self-critic mechanism.
In this case, what happens is
if you have a particular task,
in this case, where,
say, a user says,
book me a reservation
for a restaurant,
Fogo de Chao on OpenTable for
two people, on August 14, 2024,
at 7:00 PM.
And this is the current
state of the screen, where
you can see the screenshot.
Then the agent
can go and propose
a bunch of different actions.
So it can choose to go and
select the date and time.
It can choose to also
select the number of people
and then open the date selector.
It can instead search for
Terra Eataly Silicon Valley
restaurant and type that
in the search bar or it
can decide to go to
the OpenTable homepage.
And how the self-critic
mechanism works
is all these proposed actions
are passed to a critic network.
And the critic LLM is able
to go and predict, OK,
what's the best action to take?
And it's able to
give a ranking order.
OK, this is the best action
that we should go and use.
So this is rank 1.
This is rank 2.
And this is ranked 3.
And based on that, we can
go and optimize the system
to take the correct actions
and improve over time.
And finally, we
use reinforcement
learning from human
feedback, where
we used methods
like GRPO and DPO,
which are different
RL algorithms,
to be able to use
all the failures
and successful trajectories
you've collected so far
and improve the agent over them.
And so DPO is a
spatial technique
based on [INAUDIBLE] where
you can train an LLM using
preference data like
failures and successes,
and use that to improve
the model overall.
And so this is
how agent Q works,
where we create this
Monte Carlo Tree
Search to create trajectories
of successes and failures.
We can then use
self-critic mechanisms
to identify, what are
the proposed actions that
actually succeeded and failed?
And then we're able to
pass them through a DPO
to actually go and
optimize the network.
This is an example
of how this works.
So the agent starts
in the first state.
And the task, in
this case, is we
want to go and book a restaurant
reservation on OpenTable.
So first, it makes a mistake
and goes to the home page.
Then it recognizes that it made
a mistake and can backtrack.
So the blue arrow
here shows that it's
going and backtracking.
Then it can go and navigate
to the correct restaurant.
In this case, if the agent
accidentally makes a mistake
and chooses the incorrect date,
then it can again backtrack,
recover back.
Open the date selector,
choose the right date,
open the seat selection,
and then finally complete
the reservation.
And so this is how the
system is learning over time.
It's making a lot of mistakes,
but it's saving the mistakes
and over time improving on them.
We tried Agent Q in a lot
of real world scenarios,
including OpenTable
actual reservations.
So we actually spun up thousands
of robots, more like hundred
thousands of bots
that ran on OpenTable
and used our method to create
agents that are able to book
restaurants, and make
reservations, and do
a bunch of other things.
And we tried this with a lot
of different methods and models
out there.
So we tried GPT 4o
and then we found,
on this OpenTable
reservation task,
we are only able to reach
around 62.6% accuracies.
When it comes to
something like DPO,
the accuracy actually go
to something like 71%.
When we try agent Q, we are able
to make this work much, much
better.
So we are able to reach 81%
accuracy without any MCTS
as part of the method.
And when we apply
the whole technique
with MCTS, and DPO, and the
self-critique mechanisms.
We are actually able to reach
close to 95.4% accuracies.
And this is using a lot of
self-learning for the agent
to improve itself.
This takes usually less
than one day of training
for the agent to go from, I
would say, here, 20% accuracy.
That's 18.6%.
That's roughly 20%,
all the way to 95.4.
So that's a 4x improvement in
agent performance in less than
one day.
As a next topic, I'll touch
on memory and personalization.
So one way to think
about AI agents
is that they are taking
information, processing them.
OK, so imagine you
have an AI model.
What an AI model is doing,
it's taking some prompts.
So it's taking some
language tokens.
And it's outputting some
new language tokens.
And so this is acting
similar to a processor, where
if you have a CPU,
what happens is
you have some instructions,
which are usually binary
encoded that go into the CPU.
And then you have some
instructions that come out,
which are also binary encoded.
And then you do a loop
over them again and again.
And that's how normal
computers work.
You can do a very similar
thing and have this abstraction
of an AI model as acting similar
to a computer, where you have
language tokens that
are going in that
are encoded in the prompt.
And you have language
tokens coming out.
And this allows you to
think about an AI model
as being a processor that's
operating over natural language.
So this is something that
you can think about GPT 4,
for example, going
and doing this.
This is similar to some of the
older processor like MIPS32 that
used 32-bit instructions.
Right now, if you
look at GPT 4, we
are able to reach very
big context lengths.
So that's very interesting.
And when GPT 4
initially came out,
it was constrained to 8k tokens.
Now, we have 32k
tokens, and 128k tokens,
and 1 million tokens.
So the context length
of these models
is just increasing and
increasing over time.
And as the context
length increases
that also allows us to have--
A question from online can you
speak to the compute budget
for the day long run?
Was it H100s or a cluster?
The results.
Yes.
So that was all H100.
So actually, we trained the
whole models on 50 H100s
in less than one day.
Got you.
And then one
question from before,
as AI agents increasingly
emulate human behavior, what
protocols do you foresee
being implemented
to help users
distinguish between AI
and humans in conversation?
Yeah, that's very interesting.
I think that becomes a
question of security,
of how can we identify whether
it's a human or an agent.
It's actually a very
hard question right now
because you actually
have voice agents that
are effectively
able to mimic humans
and are able to pass as humans.
And that's actually happening
in the real world right now.
Over time, we will need
human proof of identity.
So this could be biometrics.
This could also be a combination
of maybe some personal data,
or some of password, or
secrets that only you know,
and you can use
that to authenticate
that you're talking to an
actual human and not an agent.
Any more questions?
Yeah.
So, [INAUDIBLE] systems fail?
So they did some
comprehensive study.
First of all, they
say MLS has been there
for more than 20 years.
You have distributed systems,
transaction processing.
So we are just having AI
covered by the same name.
And so far, I really
haven't seen anything new,
except for you have
an agent which,
instead of just having
API people coding
all the logic in
the program, you
have an agent will be
able to do something.
If given a prompt, it will
give you some results.
So how can you just putting
all agents together,
the intelligence
suddenly elevated?
So communicating between agents.
My point is, just how
communication between agents
is exactly the same as it
was before 20 years ago.
I think collaboration
between agents
is only vehicle to
elevate intelligence.
But I'm missing that part
today in the lecture.
This is actually something
that's coming next.
But just to answer
your question,
the biggest issue
is just reliability.
What happens is when all
these agents are communicating
using natural
language, that causes
a lot of miscommunication,
where maybe your agent got
the wrong instruction or failed
to understand what's happening.
And the more agents you add,
the more communication overhead
is there.
So you can imagine
if you have an agent
system with n different agents.
Then there's n squared
communication rules.
And so the amount of
error in the system
increases as quadratic.
And that makes that allows for
a lot of different mistakes
that can happen.
Suggesting you to
read [INAUDIBLE]
they've all pretty much
all the problems solved,
15 chapters of the book.
Yeah, totally.
That could be very interesting
also for the audience here.
So let's come back to this.
So one way to think
about agents is when you
have this transformer model.
The transformer model is
acting as a processor.
So it's taking
this input prompts.
And it's giving out
the output prompts.
And what you want
to do is you want
to be able to have
a memory system.
So you want to have something
like a file disk or RAM,
where you are saving
what's happening and being
able to process that over time.
So you want to have
repeated operations.
So you do the first
pass over a model.
You get some output tokens.
You can save them in
a RAM-like system.
And then you have some new
instructions that come out.
Like now, here's
step two of the plan.
Go execute that.
Here's step three of the plan.
Here's step four of the plan.
And that looping behavior,
this is, in a sense,
giving rise to agents, where
you can imagine this is--
the transformer
is the processor.
The memory system, and the
instructions, and the planning
are acting similar to the
file system and the RAM.
And so there are
overall giving rise
to this computer
architecture, where
you have the agent acting
as a computer system
with the memory processors,
which is the compute
and then being able to
use browsers, and actions,
and multi-modality, which can
be inputs like audio, and voice,
and so on.
When we think about
long-term memory,
based on the analogy
before, you can
think of this as similar to
a disk, where you want a user
memory that's long
lived and persistent.
And so that you can save
context about the user.
You can load that on the
fly whenever you want.
There's different mechanisms
for long-term memories.
The prevalent one is embeddings.
So you have
retrieval models that
can go and fetch the right
user embeddings on the fly.
So if I have a question like,
OK, does this person, Joe,
is he allergic to peanuts?
Then can the system
go and find that?
And if we have a lot of
user data about the user,
then we can use a retrieval
model to do an embedding lookup.
Find out, OK, if this is
something that we already
know about the user or not.
And based on that,
make a right judgment.
And this is something
that is very important.
You are able to see early traces
of this in systems like ChatGPT
right now.
There's still a lot
of open questions
when it comes to
long-term memory.
The first one is hierarchy.
How do we decompose memory into
more graphical structures, where
you can have
temporal persistence.
You can have more structures.
And you might also want to
think about memory as something
that is adaptable because human
memory is usually not static.
It's changing over time.
And so you also
want to think about
when you have agent
memory, how can it change?
How can it be dynamic?
How can it self-adjust?
Because the systems
are also learning.
They're improving.
And what does this dynamic
memory systems look like?
And memory leads
to personalization,
where the goal with
having long-term memory
is that you can personalize
this agents to the user.
And they're able to
understand what you like,
what you don't like.
And they're aligned
with your preferences.
So if you have this
case of maybe someone
is allergic to
peanuts and you want
to have an agent that's
ordering food on Door Dash,
then you want it
to be personalized,
so it doesn't accidentally
order something
that you're allergic to, and
how can you go and build that.
And everyone has
different preferences,
likes, and dislikes.
So when you're
designing agents, it's
very important to
actually make sure
that you can account for this.
So there might be a lot of
explicit personalization
information that
you can collect.
What does the user like?
Are they allergic to something?
What are their favorite dishes?
What seat preferences they have,
if they're flying, and so on.
There's also a lot of
implicit preferences.
So there's a lot of things
around, which brand do you like?
Do you like Adidas versus Nike?
If there were 10
items on a list,
suppose you're looking for a
housing, which one do you prefer
and why?
And those things
are very implicit.
So they're not explicitly known.
And then there are
mechanisms where
you can collect a lot of
these implicit preferences
and then personalize over time.
There's a lot of challenges
when you're building
these personalization systems.
The first one is just
user privacy and trust.
How do you actually go
and actively collect
this information?
And how do you get people
to give that to you?
There's different
methods you can
go and use to actually
collect this information.
So one is just active learning,
where you're explicitly asking
the user for their preferences.
You're asking them, OK, are
you allergic to something?
Or do you have this seat
preference and so on?
And there might also
be passive learning,
where if you can
record the users
and see what they're
doing, then you're
able to passively learn
from their preferences.
Maybe this person likes Nike
shoes because that's where--
what you have seen them
do on the computer.
And the agent is learning
from your behavior
and become better and better.
And you can learn to personalize
by supervised fine tuning, where
you are collecting a
lot of interactions.
This can also be
through human feedback,
where you can get
thumbs up or thumbs down
and use that to improve--
like this agent go and
do the right thing.
And this is something
similar to ChatGPT,
where if you like the
chat outputs, then
you can give it a thumbs up.
If you don't like it, you
give it a thumbs down.
And then this can be
used to personalize
the system over time.
So now going to agent
to agent communication.
One question online.
How do you do evaluations
on the performance of agents
that collaborate with humans?
And is it a moving target?
At what point is human
performance redundant and agents
can be fully autonomous?
I would say it's
a hard question.
You just have to go
and build benchmarks
because it's very hard
to know what's going
to happen in the real world.
Right now, I would say, based
on a lot of current state
of evaluations and
what I showed before,
agents are not really there.
The most successful
agents we have seen so far
are coding agents.
So if you have your, whatever,
intelligent code editor.
You can already see the traces.
They are automating a lot
of engineering for you
already, that you don't
have to go and write
a lot of boilerplate
code, or you
have to spend a lot of
your own time fixing bugs.
So at some point, we'll see this
thing where humans become more
like managers.
And we are giving them feedback.
We are giving them
direction, OK, we want this--
suppose you have systems
of different agents.
So you give them, OK, I want
agent 1 to go and do this.
Agent 2 to go and
do this, so on.
See what the final output is.
And over using that, improve
the overall generation process
that you are going towards.
And so this is likely
what's going to happen
is the agent systems will become
better and better executors,
where the humans
become the managers
for the systems of agents.
So when it comes to agent
to agent communication,
we think about
multi-agent architectures
and multi-agent
systems, where you
have all this cute little
digital robots that
can go and talk to each
other, communicate,
and go do your work
in a very coordinated
and streamlined manner.
There's reasons that
you want to go and build
multi-agent systems.
The first one is
parallelization.
By dividing a task
into smaller chunks
and having multiple agents.
If you have n agents
instead of one agent,
you can improve the overall
speeds and efficiencies.
The second thing
is specialization.
If you have different
specialized agents--
so you have maybe a
spreadsheet agent,
and you have a Slack agent, and
you have a web browser agent.
Then you can also
route different tasks
to different agents.
Each agent can become really,
really good at their tasks.
And this is similar to having
a degree in a specific major
or having an occupation--
specializing in that occupation.
There's a lot of challenges
when it comes to agent to agent
in communication.
The biggest one is that
this communication is lossy.
When you have one agent company
communicating to another agent,
it's possible that it
might make a mistake.
This is similar to what
happens in human organizations.
Maybe your manager will
ask you to go do something,
but you maybe misunderstood
them and did something different
or they were like, oh,
why does this happen?
And similarly, agent
to agent communication
is also fundamentally
lossy, where
whenever you are
communicating information
from one agent to another,
you are losing some percentage
of the information.
And that allows for mistakes
to propagate in that system
and become like
increasingly more prevalent.
And there's different mechanisms
for multi-agent system.
This is a very novel
field right now.
People are still trying
to figure this out.
No one has actually
cracked this right now.
What you want to do
is you want to build
the right system of
hierarchies, where
you might have
manager agents that
are working with worker agents.
You might have managers
or manager agents.
And you might have maybe
flat agents organizations,
where maybe one manager is
managing hundreds of agents,
or it could be a
vertical tree, where
you have maybe 10 different
hierarchies of agents
that are managing each other.
And so a lot of these
systems are possible.
And this just depends on
the task of what you're
doing and specializing on.
And the biggest challenge
with this kind of systems
is, how do you exchange
communication effectively
without losing that information?
How do you build
syncing primitives?
How can communication
from one agent
that's very far away from maybe
another agent in the hierarchy
go and be communicated
very, very effectively
across the chain?
There's a couple of
frameworks out there
that are looking to solve
these problems on how do we
make this communication
protocols robust
and how can we add mechanisms
to reduce this miscommunication.
A big one in this part is MCP,
which is model context protocol.
This is a protocol that
came from Anthropic
that a lot of people
are using right now.
It's a simple
wrapper around APIs.
So what it does is it gives you
a streamlined standard format
around each API.
And by creating an MCP
wrapper around your service--
so this could maybe you
have a file server service
that exposes an API.
You can create MCP wrapper
for your file server,
or maybe for your email client,
or for maybe your Slack client,
or something running
on your computer.
Then all this MCP
connected servers
can go and communicate with each
other and do things for you.
And so this allows for very
effective communication,
where you are able to
control the routing
and make the systems modular.
So you're able to plug-in
new services as you want to.
Similarly, another
framework in this space
is Agent to Agent protocol.
So this is a new protocol that
came from Google very recently,
that's allowing for
agents to also communicate
with other agents and add a
lot of reliability and fallback
mechanisms.
I'm not sure how many people
here in the room have used MCPs.
Yeah, not many.
OK, cool.
So MCPs are actually very cool.
What they are doing is they
are abstracting your APIs
and making them
very, very modular
so that you can go and plug
your API into an MCP protocol.
And once it's
wrapped around that,
then you can go
and interconnect it
to any other service
that's supported by MCPs.
So it becomes, in a sense, like
having a standard interface
for communication for
your different services
or applications you have, and
exposing them, and letting them
connect and talk to each other.
So similar to how
you have something
like HTTPS for communication
on the normal internet,
MCP becomes an interesting
protocol for communication
to happen over different agents.
And so if you have a client
like Claude, or Replit,
or some other model,
you can connect that
to servers that are
supporting the MCP protocol.
You can have a bunch
of different services.
Each services could be some of
data tool, like a database, API,
or pretty much else.
And they can all interconnect
and do modular things for you.
And because MCPs are not
dependent on the spec
of your API.
They can allow you to absorb a
lot of changes and at this level
of modularity and
abstraction by standardizing
the whole interface.
You can also have
dynamic tool discovery
because you can find
different MCP servers that
are exposed in some directory.
And then you can also
plug in MCP servers
that you like and
connect to them.
So you can plug in new
tools, spread them out.
And you can route information
based on what you want to do.
Finally, touching on some
of the issues when it
comes to agent systems.
So far, we have seen a lot
of different things, OK,
how can this agents work?
How can we evaluate them?
How can we train them?
How can we think
about communicating
with different agent systems?
And even though a lot of these
things are very interesting,
a lot of these things
are taking off,
there remains a lot key
problems in the space
that we still have to
solve for these agents
to be practical, for them to
be applied in everyday life,
and for them to
become useful for you.
The biggest one is
just reliability
that the systems have to
become very, very reliable.
They need to be close to 99.9%
reliable if you're giving them
access to your payments and
your bank details, for example,
or maybe they're connected
to your emails, calendars,
and whatever services.
And then you want to
really trust them.
You don't want the systems to go
rogue and maybe post something
wrong for you on socials--
on your Twitter,
or your LinkedIn,
or you don't want them to
go and create an havoc,
or make a wrong
transaction on your behalf.
And so that becomes,
like how can you
trust an agentic system
that's operating autonomously?
And that's where reliability
becomes a big thing.
The second issue with
autonomous agents is looping.
This agent can go
do something wrong,
so they can get stuck in a loop.
And they might just go
and repeat that process
again and again.
So if you give them
a task-- and maybe
if you remember the
restaurant booking
task that I showed before.
And maybe the agent went
to the wrong restaurant,
and it got stuck,
and maybe just trying
to do the same thing
again and again.
It doesn't know what to do.
And that kind of issues
can happen to a lot
with agents, where you might
end up wasting a lot of money
and compute.
And it's very important
to be able to figure that
out and correct that.
And that leads to a lot
of use cases around,
how can we test agents?
How can we properly
benchmark them
in the real world on a
lot of different use cases
and make sure we are
learning from that?
And how can we also, once
we deploy the systems,
be able to observe them?
And that becomes, how can
we know what is happening?
Can we monitor them online?
Can we have some
of safety, which
could be based on
audit trails, that we
can audit all the operations
that this agent has done so far?
And we can maybe also
have human overrides,
that if something goes wrong,
we have some of human fallback,
where maybe a remote operator
can take control of the agent,
and correct it, and
fix it or maybe you
are able to go and directly
take control and fix it.
This is similar to
autopilot in Tesla.
So when you're
driving autopilot,
maybe you see
something, maybe it's
going to go do something wrong.
And you can take over control
and override the system.
And that becomes
very interesting
when you're thinking about real
world deployment of agents.
Yeah, so that was a
whole lecture on agents.
Sorry, there was some things
that were a bit messy.
Yeah, we had to put
together some final slides.
Happy to take questions.
Yeah, go on.
When you say an accuracy,
say, of 40% or something
on a task over the
course of a day,
do you think that there's a
plan to get to 99 or 99.9999?
And do you have a
[INAUDIBLE] is that just
iterations on research?
Or is there actually clear
things that you need to try?
So this is definitely
possible, especially
with reinforcement learning.
And I showed the
Agent Q method before.
So right now, a lot
of these models--
even if you have Claude
Sonnet or GPT 4o, or Gemini,
they're not trained on these
agentic interfaces tasks.
So that's why-- they're
working zero shot.
So they are never trained in
their distribution training
set on actually going and
optimizing these problems.
And so when they encounter
this new interfaces
or this new tasks in the
real world, they often fail.
But if you're able to
train the systems directly
to work on this task
using reinforcement
learning, and corrections,
and self-improvement,
then you can actually reach
very, very high accuracies.
So in the OpenTable
task with Agent Q,
we reached like 95% accuracies.
And if you go and keep on
going and training the systems,
you can fully saturate
them, reach close to 99.9%
The hard thing becomes is
there's a diversity of tasks.
So I can imagine there's
millions of websites.
And if you want to
train an agent that's
using 99.9% on each website,
that's a hard challenge.
And that's something
that's very interesting.
How can you build
a generalized agent
that can work on the
whole internet, that
can generalize to everything?
Maybe in the future,
you will have
agents that can do automate
all of voice calling, all
of computer to control.
Maybe they can also use all
of the APIs and everything.
And something like that is
possible, theoretically.
It's just very
hard to build that.
Do you know whether AI agents
are able to solve captchas?
They can.
What do you think
the implications
of that are for, how
the internet's going
to work in the next 10 years?
It's definitely
very interesting.
I would say it's a
cat and mouse game.
So you have seen the new
generation of captchas,
they're becoming harder
and harder to solve.
And I think it's very
hard to beat this
because if a human can
do it, theoretically,
an agent can also go
and do the same thing.
So over time, I think we'll
have to just figure out
better methods of identity.
Biometrics can be
a big part of that.
If you are able to use
fingerprints or some
of proof mechanisms,
then we know
this is an actual
human, not an agent.
There's this article
called "AI 2027"
that you've probably heard of,
that outlined where AI research
is going to go and
what might happen.
And in 2027, after '27, when we
automate programming and then
we automate AI research.
And after your lecture,
I was wondering,
do you think we could automate
the process of creating
AI agents?
Because from what I
understand, the main bottleneck
is, how am I going
to access UIs, APIs?
How am I going to be
able to access data that
is enclosed in those, I
guess, complex and somewhat
dynamic systems?
So what if, very
simply, someone designed
an agent that was optimized
to vectorize APIs and UIs?
And then you designed
an agent that
was optimized to train agents
on different vectorized data
sets because their
specific architectures
that you can use to
train agents, whatever.
Do you think we will see, in
the future, people automating,
with confidence, our process
of creating AI agents,
making all these niche
specific AI agents that we're
seeing on the market obsolete?
Yeah, I absolutely think so.
So this is going to happen.
And I think it's already
happening in the bigger labs.
So if you have labs
like OpenAI, they
have a lot of research agents.
There's also papers
from-- if you've
seen from [INAUDIBLE] people
are working on AI research
or agents that can go and
write research papers,
and train models, and
do a bunch of things.
So it's totally
possible for agents
to go and self-improve
and build other agents.
And you can have a whole
process on how that can happen.
And definitely, it's
possible to train
on a lot of this data
sources, and APIs,
and find ways to represent
them, and collect the right sets
of data, and improve that.
I do think that seems to be
the future of a lot of maybe
hard research, especially
around protein designs and a lot
of hard sciences.
So we'll definitely see
a lot of that happen.
Hi, Garg.
Nice to meet you again.
Just to give you
context, we're building
the Slack for AI agents.
Basically, it's
Uber for AI agents.
So I've been working on
agents for a long time.
The biggest problem
with agents has
been, as you said,
reliability, and hallucination.
The first thing is--
the first thing
we try to work on
is, how do we prevent agent--
prevention from hallucinating.
The next thing is what models
were best at executing actions?
So for my research, we
realized that Claude is great.
Better still, we
have GPT at the end.
So we have-- just like Slack.
So we have a team of
agents doing work.
And then the one
that does the action
seem to be GPT agent
because we struggle
with some agents doing--
as you said, GPT 4 is
great at taking action.
And other models of GPT
seem to not work well.
Claude and other stuff.
So I think the biggest
challenge with building agents
is-- also the third one is
the fact that end users can
take one hit.
So my wife here doesn't
give-- if I give out
hotel as the product and
it makes one mistake,
there is no space for
reinforcement learning.
In the sense that if I
say book my flight, like I
told [INAUDIBLE]
to do it yesterday,
and he made one mistake
and I lost trust.
So the problem is to
work in the real world,
our agents should prevent making
mistakes in the real world.
s that brings us
to sandbox, which
I love what you're
doing with sandbox
and doing clones
of this website.
The challenge with sandbox is
you can't clone all the websites
on the internet.
And where human Excel is the
fact that if given a new task,
they figure their way around.
So these are challenges
that we have with agents.
And I'm happy if you
can talk more about it
or we can talk about it later.
Totally, totally.
Just to get the gist of it,
what's the exact question there?
So I think the question
is, how do we make
them ready for the real world?
We have a body which does
good job with calling,
but makes mistakes.
We have email agent, my own,
that got stuck in a loop
and kept sending email
five times to an investor.
We have coding agent that wiped
up 3,000 lines of code for me
yesterday.
I had to redo it.
So we have these challenges
in the real world.
And people like my wife are
not going to take one shot hit
and they will just
stop using it.
So I think the question is,
how do we prevent agents
from hallucinating?
Yeah, so it's definitely
a hard problem.
You can go and keep
improving the agents.
Even if you look at maybe a
lot of the initial models that
came out, when you had the first
versions of GPT 3 and so on,
they hallucinated a lot.
But as you have bigger
models, more parameter size
and are trained
on more data, they
start hallucinating less, so
if you see the new generation
of models GPT 4 and Claude.
I think over time, I
think, as you figure out
how to make better
foundation models,
a lot of these errors
in the systems go down,
especially hallucinations and
other things that can happen.
You just require a
lot of monitoring,
and evaluations, and
a lot of testing.
And this also becomes
very domain specific.
So if you're working
on something that's
a domain specific
problem and you're like,
OK, you want an agent that
can work 99.9% on this domain,
then what you want
to do is you want
to create the right test cases.
You can be like, OK, here's
1,000 scenarios that we really
go and care about.
Can we go and test this agent
on this 1,000 scenarios all
the time, which could
be in production,
when you are actually running
this with your users or this
could be some of
offline simulation,
where you have daily testing.
Is there any regressions
in the system?
What happens if you
change a prompt?
What will this look like?
And if you're able to build
a lot of very robust testing,
then you can also verify
your accuracies are going up.
And then it becomes stable.
Can you fine tune this agents
to become better and better
for your use cases?
So I think I would say
the correct answer is
a combination of
models will become
better and better over time, so
you can just implicitly trust
them more as new
model comes out.
And the second
thing becomes, you
want to have very domain
specific testing and evaluation.
So for your own
use case, can you
go and have some ways to rank
which model is doing what?
How good is it?
And make the right judgment,
and be able to fine tune,
and use reinforcement
learning and other techniques
to make them better over time.
What do you think about smaller
model [INAUDIBLE] reinforcement
learning because I think the
problem with large language
models--
I don't think you
need bigger brains.
You just need smarter brains.
[INAUDIBLE] much
smaller language models.
So the question
again is what do you
think about small language
models versus large language
models for agents, specifically?
Yeah, so that's an
interesting question.
I would say we are already
seeing some hints of this.
So if you look at a
lot of the newer models
that are trained on
reasoning traces,
and we have found
you can actually
train smaller models
on reasoning traces
and have a better accuracies.
So a lot of the newer GPT
4 models, all the GPT 4o,
and all the new
series of O3 Mini,
and so on, they're actually
distilled small models,
but they're just fine tuned
using reinforcement learning
and other techniques to
be very good at reasoning.
And so we're already seeing
that with all the new generation
of all the thinking
models that are coming out
and all the O1 and O3 series.
So that's showing this
that smaller models
with better reasoning,
better processing,
it's actually the right answer.
It will be interesting to see
how far can you push the limits
and what will this look
like maybe over this year.
What are the best
accuracies we can
expect from this kind
of reasoning things?
Can we actually go and be
PhD level at mathematics
and even superintelligence on
a lot of this specific domains?
I think the litmus
test is real world.
And my approach architecture,
which I think may work,
is the manager agent could
be large language model.
And the worker agent could
be small language models
because I think this
distillation happening when they
are collaborating in a team.
The last question
is regarding memory.
The analogy you gave with
respect to a computer.
We have random access memory.
We have the ROM.
And then we have the hard drive.
With AI agents,
right now, I just
think they have
random access memory.
And with Mem 0, we are
just giving it ROM.
I don't think they have the hard
drive and this consciousness
while they are working.
I think that's a challenge.
I would like to know, how
do we implement that system
to make it like a computer?
Yeah, that's an
interesting question.
I would be curious
if you actually try
and experiment and
see how that works.
Obviously, there's no
straight answer to this.
It just depends on
what you're building,
what your applications are.
And then just depending
on what you're doing,
there can be different sizes of
models that might work better.
If you're doing a
coding task, you
might want more
of a coding model
versus if you're doing something
more chat-based, or actions,
and so on.
And I think you just have to
find the right ingredients,
in a sense, the right
components for your application.
And then go and build that.
Yeah, so there's no right
answer to it in a sense.